# Rafal Szymanski

### **Quality Inspector**

Nashua, NH - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Rafal-Szymanski/c876a1ff47453d2f

To play an instrumental role in the continued/future success of an established manufacturing company by becoming their top Quality Inspector, where I may apply extensive experience gained from the quality control field during the last 17 years.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Quality Inspector**

Lytron Inc - Woburn, MA - September 2010 to Present

#### **METROLOGY**

- Proficient setting up and using a micrometer, caliper, height gage, indicator, surface plate, sine plate, profilometer, cylindrical plug/ring, thread gage, optical comparator, coordinate measuring machine, video comparator (Micro Vu), etc.
- Experience working on Brown & Sharp CMM's as both operator and programmer using multiple versions of PC-DMIS software.
- Can create coordinate measuring machine inspection programs off-line as well as online.
- Have set up and maintained various types of testing stations.

#### **INSPECTION**

- Was responsible for inspecting a wide variety of mechanical and electrical products.
- Performed complex incoming, first piece, in-process, final floor or batch inpection on a wide variety of parts and products.
- Performed necessary inspection of prototype products and on occasion worked with engineers to devise the best inspection technique.
- · Perform first article inspections.
- Incoming inspections of raw materials, laser etching, coating verifications, and final lot releases to insure that all quality requirements are as specified in the purchase order.
- Good visual inspection experience screening for damage, completeness, proper identification and paper work.
- Assist engineering in investigations of process related to quality issues.

#### DRAWINGS AND DOCUMENTATION

- Understand complex blueprints, assembly prints, specifications, and process sheets.
- Document inspection results by completing reports and logs; summarize re-work and waste; enter data into quality database, maintain charts and inspection reports.
- Worked with ASME Y14.5M (geometric dimensioning & tolerancing) drawings on a daily basis.
- Follow inspection procedures and work instructions.
- Write non-conforming material reports.
- Experience working in ISO9001 and AS9100 certified environments.

### **Quality Control Technician II,**

Hologic Inc - Marlborough, MA - February 2013 to June 2014

- The primary role of this position was to perform Incoming / In-Process inspection on mechanical / electrical components. It also include some level of final inspection. Device History record reviews while supporting the equipment control system as needed.
- Preform Incoming / In-Process inspection on mechanical / electrical components using standard inspection equipment such as Height Gauges, Surface Plates, Verniers, Dial Indicators, Ring / Plug Gauges, Optical Comparators, Cmm ECT.
- Complete and review Incoming, In-Process and Final inspection documentation.(Components Inspection Folders, checklist, release forms, calibration data records.
- Issue Non-Conformance Reports (NCR's) of Nonconformance's.
- Preform inspections as requested for Engineering and other departments. (First Article and Courtesy
  inspection) and assist with the development of applicable inspection procedures, checklist, forms and
  Inspection Folders.
- Maintain QC Activity Collection Plans and other applicable tracking logs. Supporting the Equipment Control System as needed which include activities such as:

Calibrating and Shipping Fixture Kits.

- Gathering and shipping Equipment out to Calibration suppliers.
- Assisting with On-Site Calibrations, Data Entry.

### **Quality Inspector**

Lab Medical Manufacturing INC. - Billerica, MA - June 1998 to August 2010

- •Lab Medical designs Various Medical Hand instruments for some of the worlds largest medical manufacturing companies. With my experience and knowledge I help Lab medical achieve their goal.
- Standard measuring tools: Micrometers, Caliper, Dial & Height gages, indicators, Comparator, Coordinate Measuring Machine, Micro Vu.
- Perform various inspections such as first article inspections. Incoming inspections of raw materials, Laser etching, coating verifications, and final lot releases.
- Reading drawings, blue prints and process sheets.
- Inspection parts per procedures and work instructions.
- Experience with ISO9100.
- Inspect incoming raw material to insure that all quality requirements are as specified in the purchase order.
- To inspect for damage and completeness, proper identification as well as paper work.
- Visual and dimensional inspection of In-process, components, as well as final product inspection.
- Assist engineering in investigations of process related to quality issues.
- Write Non Conforming Materials Reports.
- Documents inspection results by completing reports and logs; summarizing re-work and waste; inputting data into quality database.

#### **QA Line Auditor**

Boston Acoustics - Peabody, MA - 2004 to 2005

Test and troubleshoot power amps during Incoming inspection, finished product inspections, as well as inprocess auditing.

- Inspecting incoming materials as well as final products.
- Work with engineers to follow through with corrective actions.
- Set up and maintain testing stations.
- Maintaining charts as well as inspection reports.

### **EDUCATION**

## **PC-DMIS Programming Level 1**

HEXAGON METROLOGY 2011

# **Certified Quality Inspector**

American Society For Quality - Boston, MA 2009

# A.S. Degree in Computer Science

Quincy College 2002